（サイ）ナルト　また　みんなに
チャクラを渡せないのかい？
Naruto...
Can you share your chakra
with everyone again?
（ナルト）今は無理だ。
I can't right now!
九喇嘛のチャクラが
まだ溜まりきってねえ。
Kurama hasn't finished
amassing chakra yet!
本体を倒すには
あのデカブツをなぎ払いつつ→
In order to take down
the main body,
we need to mow down the big ones
and slip past them.
間をすり抜けていくしか方法が…。
一気にジャンプして
近づける距離でもない。
The distance is too great to
make a single leap for it.
敵の攻撃を弾き→
We also need time to weave signs
and repel the enemy's attacks.
印を結ぶ時間もいる。
ナルトのチャクラがない以上→
Without your chakra, Naruto,
深手を負う可能性が高いのに→
it's very likely we'll suffer
heavy casualties.
医療班は　前に出られない。
And the Medical Corps can't
come up to the front.
（サスケ）なぎ払い　すり抜ける
何の造作もない。
Mow down and slip past?
Easy.
一気にジャンプして近づけるうえに→
This guy has the power to clear
the distance in a single leap
攻撃も弾く力もあんぜ　こいつは。
and repel enemy attacks.
（サクラ）みんなが深手を負っても→
I can now stay nearby and
常にそばにいて
回復してあげられる　今の私なら。
heal anyone who suffers
serious injuries at all times.
（３人）口寄せの術。
- Summoning Jutsu!
- Summoning Jutsu! - Summoning Jutsu!
akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
The New Three-Way Deadlock
Huh?
あれ　ん？
Wait...
この色。
This color...
You're...
お前…　ガマ吉じゃねえかよ。
Gamakichi!
Pop was tied up with
some negotiations,
（ガマ吉）親父は
今　手打ちのゴタゴタじゃけん→
so I came in his place.
俺が来たで　びっくりしたか？
You surprised?!
No! No!
いや…　いや　いや　いや　いや…。
But man, you sure got big
all of a sudden!
それより
一気にでかくなったな　お前。
I'm more shocked than
I was about Akamaru!
赤丸んときより
びっくりしたってばよ。
You humans grow too slow, that's all.
お前ら人間の成長が
遅すぎるんじゃ！
Anyway, what's up?
それより　用件は何じゃ？
Right!
おう　奥のほうに
でっけえのがいんだろ。
See the gigantic guy way
in the back?
Could you get me closer to it
with a big leap?
あれに大ジャンプで近づいてくれ。
（ガマ吉）あの　いちばんでかいのか？
You mean the biggest one
over there?
Yeah.
ああ。
（アオダ）サスケ様　いかように？
Lord Sasuke, your desire?
I need you to just keep
advancing forward.
お前は
まっすぐに進むだけでいい。
奥の本体は　俺がやる。
I'll get the real body in the back!
Sakura dear!
（カツユ）サクラちゃん　ついに→
You're finally able to invoke
the 100 Healings Mark!
百豪の印を発動できたのですね。
Lady Tsunade would be so proud...
綱手様も　きっとお喜びに。
Lady Katsuyu, we don't have time...
（サクラ）カツユ様　今は　それより→
Please divide and attend to each person
in the Allied Shinobi Forces.
分裂して　連合のみんなに
１人ずつついてください。
Our role will be to heal everyone.
私たちは　回復役です。
I never expected
（ミナト）まさか　もう一度→
to see the Three-Way Deadlock
Summoning again!
口寄せ三竦みが見られるとは
思わなかったな。
フフッ…。
It is a new era!
《新たな時代よ…》
Go!
行け！
Go! Aoda!
行け　アオダ。
Lady Katsuyu, please proceed!
お願いします　カツユ様。
Jump, Gamakichi!
ジャンプだ　ガマ吉。
クッ…。
This is the original Team 7...
《これが元の七班…》
Nice, Gamakichi!
いいぞ　ガマ吉！
だてにでかくなってねえな。
Your size isn't just for show, eh!
Nevermind that, just hurry up
and weave your jutsu signs!
そがいなことよりのう→
はよう術の印を結べっちゃ
ほんまに。
Get with it,
or I'll shake you off my head.
オラオラ　頭から振り落とすぞ。
Even his attitude has gotten bigger!
《態度は　更にでかく》
I know!
わかってるってばよ！
うわっ！　なっ　なんだ！？
What's going on?
It's all right.
大丈夫　このナメクジは
五代目火影の回復術です。
These slugs are part
of the Fifth Hokage's Healing Jutsu.
Please do not worry.
心配しないでください。
My strength is being restored!
《力が　戻ってくる》
My wounds are...
傷が。
治癒して。
It's healing me...
《さっき　百豪の印を
発動したばかりなのに→
Her 100 Healings Mark was
only just activated!
And yet she can already perform
Lady Katsuyu's long-distance healing!
カツユ様の遠隔治癒まで
こなすなんて→
Sakura... You are simply amazing!
サクラ　あんたって子は
ほんとにもう！》
Lord Sasuke?
（アオダ）サスケ様。
そのまま行け。
Keep moving forward.
サスケ！
Sasuke!
Go for it!
《キバ：いきやがれ！》
《シノ：やれ！》
Do it!
Hang in there!
《ヒナタ：頑張って！》
《シカマル：よく狙え》
Aim well!
You can do it!
《チョウジ：いけるよ！》
《いの：やっちゃえ！》
Give it to 'em!
Yes!
《うん！》
Wind Style: Massive Rasen Shuriken!
風遁　超大玉螺旋手裏剣！
Inferno Style: Susano'o Flame Control!
炎遁　須佐能乎加具土命！
Sasuke and I must've been
compatible, after all...
((俺ってば
サスケとの相性よかったんだな。
（ヤマト）ああ　雷に勝てるのは
風だけだ。
Yes...
Only "Wind" can beat "Lightning."
No...
(いや　そっちじゃなくて))
That's not what I meant.
Only "Wind" can assist
and magnify "Fire"...
((火を助けて
更に大きな力にできるのは→
(風の力だけだってことだ))
It's hit!
当たった！
本当に当たったぞ！
It really hit!
I don't recall ever seeing
a Flame Control of that magnitude.
《扉間：あれほどの加具土命を
見た覚えがない。
まったく同じチャクラ比で
術を合わせたか》
And they combined jutsu
with matching chakra ratios!
熟年のコンビでも難しいぞ。
That's difficult even for
a seasoned duo!
風車のような手裏剣に
漆の光沢より黒い矢。
A windmill-like shuriken,
and an arrow blacker than lacquer...
Let's name it
名付けて
灼遁　光輪疾風漆黒矢零式！
the Scorch Style Nimbus Gale
Jet Black Arrow Formation Zero!
フッ　いや　ないな。
Nah, never mind.
ヘッ！
Burn away...
燃え尽きろ。
サスケの言ったこと
キミも　見て聞いていただろう。
You heard what
Sasuke said earlier, didn't you?
What are his true intentions?
彼の本当の狙いは　なんなんだ。
（重吾）さあな。
I have no idea.
Damn it!
《香燐：クソ！　なんでサスケと
別行動なんだよ！
Why did we branch off from Sasuke?
This wasn't the deal!
話が違くねえ？》
I'm safe!
《水月：助かった　最前線なんて
まっぴらごめんだっつうの》
No thanks to being on the frontlines!
There they are.
（大蛇丸）あそこね。
Look at the sorry state
you're in, Tsunade.
（大蛇丸）
ずいぶんなザマね…　綱手。
Gross... A gigantic slug...
（水月）げぇ～　でっかいナメクジ！
How much salt would
you need to take it down?
倒すのに　塩どんだけいるかな。
That's just one part of Katsuyu
あれは　湿骨林から
口寄せされたカツユの　ほんの一部。
that was summoned from
Shikkotsu Woods.
I'd say it's pretty small, actually.
あれでも　すごく小さいほうよ。
へぇ～。
You don't say.
I thought we were here
for the Five Kage, not the slugs.
今は　ナメクジより
五影のことだろ。
Lord Orochimaru,
stop paying attention to Suigetsu
大蛇丸様も　いちいち
そいつの言うこと→
気にしないでいいからさ。
さっさと用事済ませてさ。
and get to the task at hand.
サスケ君と離して
こっちに連れてきたのが→
Are you that upset because
you couldn't stay with Sasuke?
そんなに不服？
そのとおり…　じゃねえよし！
That's totally... not the case!
Let's just do this.
さっさ行くの…　水月てめえ！
Damn you, Suigetsu!
Why are you picking on me?
なんで僕が責められんの？
Doesn't everyone who sees
a slug want to sprinkle salt on it?
ナメクジ見たら
塩かけたくなるもんでしょ→
誰だって。
（大蛇丸）まずは　綱手ね。
Tsunade first!
Let's go.
行くわよ。
Lady Tsunade!
（カツユ）綱手様！
Wait, was the Hokage
always a granny?
あれ？　火影って
ばばあだったっけ？
Ugh...
うげっ！　これって
胴長じゃないもんね…　やっぱ。
It's not like she had a really
long torso either, right?
It seems you were reckless, Tsunade.
無茶をしたようね　綱手。
Orochimaru?
（綱手）大蛇丸…。
Katsuyu...
カツユ　私は五影の処置をしに
ここへ来た。
I came here to aid the Five Kage.
I'm not an enemy.
敵じゃないわ。
I have no reason to believe you.
信じられる根拠がありません。
Besides, you were dead!
それに　あなたは死んだはずです。
うぅっ！
怪しい行動をしたと思うなら→
If I do anything that
strikes you as suspect,
you're welcome to kill me
once and for all with your acid.
酸で　今度こそ
ほんとに殺すといいわ。
ひ～っ！
All right.
わかりました
あなたを信じましょう。
I'll believe you.
You're quite sensible, unlike Manda.
マンダと違って　ものわかりがいい。
Now then...
さて…　ではまず。
First of all...
Where are the other Kage?
（大蛇丸）他の影たちはどこ？
They're recovering inside
my fragments.
私の分裂体の中で　回復中です。
They sustained serious injuries,
and it's very...
皆さん重傷で　なかなか…。
But Katsuyu...
（大蛇丸）
しかし　カツユ　あなたがいて→
With you here, why is it taking
so long for them to heal?
なぜ回復がこの程度なの？
I can only use my power
in response
私は　綱手様の百豪の力に呼応して
力を使うことができます。
to the strength of
Lady Tsunade's 100 Healings.
But Lady Tsunade is
extremely weak right now,
（カツユ）今の綱手様は
すごく弱っておいでで→
so I'm not able to activate
my strength fully.
私の力を
十分に発動できないのです。
Is that how the system worked?
そういうシステムだったかしら…。
Anyway, whatever I remember,
I've never seen Tsunade so weak.
まぁ　よく思い出してみても→
ここまで弱った綱手を
初めて見るから　そうなのね。
So it must be true.
I am trying to persevere
and focus on healing,
口寄せが解けかかっているのを
どうにか　こらえつつ→
despite the Summoning
starting to unravel.
回復に集中している状態です。
That's why I haven't been able
to properly reattach her body.
（カツユ）なので　綱手様の体を
上手くつなげることもできず…。
Suigetsu, bring Tsunade's lower half
and join it to her upper half.
水月　綱手の下半身を持って
上半身とつなげなさい。
Huh?!
え～っ！？　バラすほうが
得意なんすけど。
I'm better at cutting things up.
Ugh...
うげ～っ。
The slugs are all slimy
and wriggly. Gross!
ナメクジが濡れて　グネグネ気持悪いよ。
Well, so are you, Suigetsu!
そりゃお前もだろうが。
In fact, you're grosser and weirder
because you have a human form!
人型の分
お前のほうが気持悪いし　変だろ。
Karin...
香燐　あなたは噛ませて
回復させてあげなさい。
Let her bite you
so that she can heal.
What? I don't want anyone
but Sasuke biting me...
え～　サスケ以外に噛まれるの
やだなぁ　うち。
Hah! You just admitted
you're in love with Sasuke!
あ～　サスケ好きを公言したね　今。
Huh?
You're wrong!
はっ！　ち　違っ　あんなクソ野郎。
How could I hate,
I mean, like that damn Sasuke?
サスケが…　くね～だろが！
What are you saying?
何言ってんの？
う　うちを殺しかけたのが…。
He tried to kill me...
And it was irresistible...
たまらない…　違うか。
No, it wasn't!
フッ　サスケに噛まれる前から
歯形だらけだろ　キミ。
You were covered in bite marks
long before Sasuke bit you!
Shut up!
うっせえ！
今はサスケ専用なんだよ！
Right now, I'm exclusively for Sasuke.
Don't be so defiant,
you denture mold model.
開き直んな　入れ歯製造機。
Besides, how does
your body work anyway?
だいたい　どういうシステムだよ
キミの体は。
You're the weird one.
キミのほうが変だろ。
んだと～　こら！
What? Say that again!
You two...
あなたたち　さっさとなさい。
Make it snappy.
You're both weird.
変なのはお互いさまでしょう。
ケンカはよしなさい。
So stop fighting.
さもないと　私の蛇で縛り上げ→
Or else...
I'll have my snakes ties you up
口から入り込んで
体を乗っ取るわよ。
and crawl into your mouth
and possess you.
You're the weirdest one
among us all!
《あんたが
いちばん変なんだよ》
He's weird and he's abnormal.
WEIRD
《変態で変体なんだよ》
ABNORMAL
She's taking so much,
I might end up aging into a hag.
《吸い取られすぎて
うちが老けそう》
Lady Tsunade,
you're going to be all right!
綱手様　もう大丈夫です。
綱手　少しは私に感謝しなさい。
Tsunade, be a little grateful to me.
You betrayed the village...
So why all of this now?
里を裏切ったお前が今更　なぜだ？
The range of things that
interest me has expanded.
今はいろいろと
興味の幅が広がってね。
昔は自らが風となり
風車を回したいと思ってたわ。
In the past, I wanted to become
the wind and turn the windmill myself.
But now, I know the pleasure
（大蛇丸）でも今は
いつ吹くかもわからない→
of waiting around for
someone else's wind.
他の風を待つ楽しさも知れた。
One that is unpredictable.
その風を楽しむ前に
密封されたくはないからね。
And I don't want that wind to
get sealed away before I can enjoy it.
相変わらず訳のわからんことを。
You still don't make any sense.
But... I suppose you've changed a little.
だが　少し変わったか。
まさか　お前に助けられるとはね。
そんなこともあるわよ。
I never imagined you would save me...
Even that is possible.
Do you remember?
覚えているか？
あのときの三竦み。
The Three-Way Deadlock
from that time?
口寄せの…。
The summoning...
No...
違う。　文字通りの三竦み。
Just like how it's written...
The Three-Way Deadlock...
Earth Style Stone Pistol Jutsu!
((土遁　岩鉄砲の術！
（自来也）ハァ　ハァ…。
It's useless, Tsunade.
無駄よ　綱手。
The Earth Style of the Hidden Stone
will most likely
岩隠れの土遁は
やがてこの山を崩す。
cause this mountain to collapse.
If we're going to escape,
we can't wait.
逃げるなら猶予はない。
あなたと私なら。
Just the two of us.
Jiraiya... too!
自来也もだ。
自来也を連れて→
We can't take Jiraiya
and outrun them.
彼らから
脱出することはできないわ。
That's why I'll use Medical Ninjutsu to...
だから　私が医療忍術を…。
Tsunade, this is war.
綱手　今は戦争よ。
We can't let our emotions
get in the way
不確定な情をさしはさんで
確率を下げたりはできない。
and lower the probability of success.
And what is success?
確率って何だ！
To survive.
私たちが生き残る確率よ。
One alone can't. Two probably can.
１人ではダメ　２人ならなんとか。
Three spells...
３人じゃ…　全滅する。
certain death.
Go on ahead.
あなたは続けてなさい。
I'll take care of Jiraiya...
いいわ　私が自来也を…。
Make one move... and I'll kill you.
一歩でも動けば　私がお前を殺す。
Seems like we're in
a three-way deadlock.
どうやら三竦みってとこね。
What are you talking about?
何を言うの？　あなたと私→
It just boils down to who will act first.
どちらが先手を取るかで決まる。
Jiraiya is already...
自来也はもう…　うっ。
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
んん…。
Jiraiya trusts you completely.
自来也は　お前のことを
心底信用している。
So much so, that it might freeze you
in your tracks.
お前を竦ませるに十分なほど。
So foolish!
くだらない。
I'll...!
私は…。
おい　自来也　綱手　大蛇丸！
Hey! Jiraiya, Tsunade, Orochimaru!
I've brought reinforcements!
(援軍を呼んできたぞ！))
People can change.
人は　変わるものよ。
Or they die before they do.
It's one or the other.
それか　その前に死ぬかの２つ。
Although he died without changing...
彼は
そのままで逝っちゃったけど。
最後まで　お前を
信用していたんだろうな。
He probably trusted you
until the very end.
Orochimaru...
大蛇丸　お前がもっと早く
そうなってくれたなら→
If you were like this sooner,
Jiraiya might not have had to die...
自来也も死なずに…。
それはそれで→
And if I had...
Jiraiya might have changed too.
自来也が変わってしまったかも。
Like how it was for us,
the Legendary Sannin,
私たち三忍がそうだったように→
things don't always go
the way you want them to.
物事は　そう都合よくは
いかないものよ。
We're not made of stone.
Distortions will appear somewhere.
一枚岩じゃいられない。
どこかに
ゆがみができるものでしょう。
Perhaps that's why I want
to observe Sasuke's future.
《だからこそサスケ君の行く末を
見てみたいのかもね。
While patiently waiting
for his wind to blow.
彼の風をゆっくりと待ちながら》
まあ　いい。
Fine. I thank you for helping me heal.
回復させてくれたことには
感謝する。
So... Do you know about the war?
で　戦争のことは知っているのか？
Of course. That's why
I'm helping you out like this.
もちろん　だからこうして
協力してるのよ　あなたに。
How long have I been like this?
どれくらい　ここに…。
I can report on the battle situation.
（カツユ）私が戦況を報告します。
How did you end up on the front?
お前　どうやって戦場に？
I see...
《そうか　サクラがカツユを》
Sakura summoned Katsuyu!
Around now,
a new Three-Way Deadlock
（大蛇丸）今頃は
新たなる三竦みが→
is probably making their debut.
お披露目されてるんじゃ
ないかしらね。
ん？
What?
Well, we're heading back.
じゃあ　私たちはもう行くわ。
You should work on healing
the other Kage.
あなたは影たちの回復に
集中することね。
koushite ima mo kawarazu
Even now, I haven't changed
donna tsuyoi nami ni mo sakarau
I'll fight any wave, no matter how strong it is
soko ni wa nakama, haruka kanata
My friends are far away
deatta subete ga ore no takara
Everyone I meet is my treasure
kono sora e habataiteku
I'll fly through this sky
ore kara shinjiru anata ni eeru
I believe in you and I'll yell out to you
toki ni wa warai naite
Sometimes I laugh or cry
donna ni fumareyouto hana wa saiteru
The flowers still bloom,
no matter how many times they've been trampled on
datte kimetakara
It's because I've made up my mind
donna ni fumarete mo saiteta hana
I'll rise up like a blooming flower
no you ni motto takaku
No matter how many times it gets trampled
sore ga naniyori mo chikara hanatsu
It unleashes more power than anything
aitsu no bun made tsuyoku ikite
I want to live resiliently for their sake too
dare ni mo makenai tsuyoi ishide
With a powerful will, I won't give in to anyone
susume kitto susumeru
Move ahead, I'm sure I'll move ahead
dare mo mitakotonai sekai wo tsukureru
I can create a world that no one has seen before
kowakunai soba ni iru kagiri
I'm not afraid, as long as you're by my side
mawari ni wa nakama ya famirii
Surrounded by friends and family
sono chikara ga michishirube ni naru
Their power shows me the way
minna kara moratta kono te ni love
In my hand, I hold what everyone has given me Love
kono machi ni fuku kaze ni noru
I'll ride the wind that blows through this city
gooru wa mada hodo tooku
I'm still a long way from my goal
demo shitteru mada yare n datte
But I know that I can still go on
dakara sakebu kono koe kareru made
So I'll cry out until I lose my voice
kono sekai wa mienu mono bakari de
This world is full of things I can't see
kowai kara jibunjishin wo kizutsuketa
I hurt myself because I was afraid of them
kirisaita yami no saki ni mieta mono
When I cut through the darkness, I saw something
massugu ni misueta mama de
I continue to gaze straight ahead
hanasanai
And never let go
There is doubt in your heart.
Won't you stop this?
It's because of that,
I want to repudiate everything.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
I can't see you not understanding
Naruto's feelings.
美空ひばりです。
There is nothing in my heart!
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
Do you really think that such things
can fill the hole in your heart?
お楽しみください。
Just like it was with me!
Isn't that right Kakashi?
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Kakashi vs. Obito"
オープニングを飾るのは
『こんにちは赤ちゃん』。
This is the only thing
the current me can do...
梓みちよさんです。